<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pigsty – Cloud</title>
    <link>/categories/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Pigsty</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/categories/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: FinOps: Endgame Cloud-Exit</title>
      <link>/blog/cloud/finops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cloud/finops/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
        <![CDATA[<img src="/zh/blog/cloud/finops/featured_hu17e563573b532c1d4edf02ebcd48a2b6_1713581_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="640"/>]]>
        
        &lt;p&gt;At the SACC 2023 FinOps session, I fiercely criticized cloud vendors. This is a transcript of my speech, introducing the ultimate FinOps concept — &lt;strong&gt;cloud-exit&lt;/strong&gt; and its best practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL; DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misaligned FinOps Focus&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Total Cost = Unit Price x Quantity&lt;/strong&gt;. FinOps efforts are centered around reducing the &lt;strong&gt;quantity&lt;/strong&gt; of wasted resources, deliberately ignoring the elephant in the room — &lt;strong&gt;cloud resource unit price&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Cloud as a Slaughterhouse&lt;/strong&gt;: Attract customers with cheap EC2/S3, then slaughter them with EBS/RDS. The cost of cloud compute is five times that of in-house, while block storage costs can be over a hundred times more, making it the ultimate cost assassin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Endgame of FinOps is Going Off-Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;: For enterprises of a certain scale, the cost of in-house IDC is around 10% of the list price of cloud services. Going off-cloud is both the endgame of orthodox FinOps and the starting point of true FinOps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In-house Capabilities Determine Bargaining Power&lt;/strong&gt;: Users with in-house capabilities can negotiate extremely low discounts even without going off-cloud, while companies without in-house capabilities can only pay a high &amp;ldquo;no-expert tax&amp;rdquo; to public cloud vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databases are Key to In-House Transition&lt;/strong&gt;: Migrating stateless applications on K8S and data warehouses is relatively easy. The real challenge is building databases in-house without compromising &lt;strong&gt;quality and security&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/Yp_PU8nmyK-NVq0clD98RQ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/blog/hero/finops.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;misaligned-finops-focus&#34;&gt;Misaligned FinOps Focus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to the amount of waste, the unit price of resources is the key point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FinOps Foundation states that FinOps focuses on &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;cloud cost optimization&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;. However, we believe that emphasizing only &lt;strong&gt;public clouds&lt;/strong&gt; deliberately narrows this concept — the focus should be on the cost control and optimization of &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; resources, not just those on public clouds — including &amp;ldquo;hybrid clouds&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;private clouds&amp;rdquo;. Even without using public clouds, some FinOps methodologies can still be applied to the entire K8S cloud-native ecosystem. Because of this, many involved in FinOps are led astray — their focus is limited to &lt;strong&gt;reducing the quantity of cloud resource waste&lt;/strong&gt;, neglecting a very important issue: &lt;strong&gt;unit price&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total cost&lt;/strong&gt; depends on two factors: &lt;strong&gt;Quantity ✖️ Unit Price&lt;/strong&gt;. Compared to quantity, &lt;strong&gt;unit price might be the key to cost reduction and efficiency improvement&lt;/strong&gt;. Previous speakers mentioned that about 1/3 of cloud resources are wasted on average, which is the optimization space for FinOps. However, if you use non-elastic services on public clouds, the &lt;strong&gt;unit price of the resources&lt;/strong&gt; you use is already several to dozens of times higher, making the wasted portion negligible in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first stop of my career, I experienced a FinOps movement firsthand. Our BU was among the first internal users of Alibaba Cloud and also where the &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;data middle platform&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; concept originated. Alibaba Cloud sent over a dozen engineers to help us migrate to the cloud. After migrating to ODPS, our annual storage and computing costs were &lt;strong&gt;70 million&lt;/strong&gt;, and through FinOps methods like health scoring, we did optimize and save tens of millions. However, running the same services with an in-house Hadoop suite in our data center cost &lt;strong&gt;less than 10 million annually&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;strong&gt;savings are good, but they&amp;rsquo;re nothing compared to the multiplied resource costs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As cost reduction and efficiency become the main theme, cloud repatriation is becoming a trend. Alibaba, the inventor of the middle platform concept, has already started dismantling its own middle platform. Yet, many companies are still falling into the trap of the slaughterhouse, repeating the old path of cloud migration - cloud repatriation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;public-clouds-a-slaughterhouse-in-disguise&#34;&gt;Public Clouds: A Slaughterhouse in Disguise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attract customers with cheap EC2/S3, then slaughter them with EBS/RDS pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elasticity touted by public clouds is designed for their business model: &lt;strong&gt;low startup costs, exorbitant maintenance costs&lt;/strong&gt;. Low initial costs lure users onto the cloud, and its good elasticity can adapt to business growth at any time. However, once the business stabilizes, vendor lock-in occurs, making it difficult to switch providers without incurring high costs, turning maintenance into a financial nightmare for users. This model is colloquially known as a &lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/ebs/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pig slaughterhouse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To slaughter pigs, one must first raise them&lt;/strong&gt;. You can&amp;rsquo;t catch a wolf without putting your child at risk. Hence, for new users, startups, and small businesses, public clouds offer sweet deals, even at a loss, to make noise and attract business. New users get first-time discounts, startups receive free or half-price credits, and there&amp;rsquo;s a sophisticated pricing strategy. Taking AWS RDS pricing as an example, the mini models with 1 or 2 cores are priced at just &lt;strong&gt;a few dollars per core per month&lt;/strong&gt;, translating to a few hundred yuan per year (excluding storage). This is an affordable option for those needing a low-usage database for small data storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/blog/cloud/finops-1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, even a slight increase in configuration leads to a &lt;strong&gt;magnitude&lt;/strong&gt; increase in the price per core month, skyrocketing to twenty or thirty to a hundred dollars, sometimes even more — not to mention the shocking EBS prices. Users may only realize what has happened when they see the exorbitant bill suddenly appearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to in-house solutions, &lt;strong&gt;the price of cloud resources is generally several to more than ten times higher, with a rent-to-buy ratio ranging from a few days to several months&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, the cost of a physical server core month in an IDC, including all costs for network, electricity, maintenance, and IT staff, is about 19 yuan. Using a K8S container private cloud, the cost of a virtual core month is only 7 yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the price per core month for Alibaba Cloud&amp;rsquo;s ECS is a couple of hundred yuan, and for AWS EC2, it&amp;rsquo;s two to three hundred yuan. If you &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t care about elasticity&amp;rdquo; and prepay for three years, you can usually get a discount of about 50-60%. But no matter how you calculate it, the price difference between cloud computing power and local in-house computing power is there and significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/blog/cloud/finops-2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pricing of &lt;strong&gt;cloud storage&lt;/strong&gt; resources is even more outrageous. A common 3.2 TB enterprise-grade NVMe SSD, with its formidable performance, reliability, and cost-effectiveness, has a wholesale price of just over &lt;strong&gt;¥3000&lt;/strong&gt;, significantly outperforming older storage solutions. However, for the same storage on the cloud, providers dare to charge 100 times the price. Compared to direct hardware procurement, &lt;strong&gt;the cost of AWS EBS io2 is 120 times higher, while Alibaba Cloud&amp;rsquo;s ESSD PL3 is 200 times higher&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a 3.2TB enterprise-grade PCI-E SSD card as a benchmark, &lt;strong&gt;the rent-to-buy ratio on AWS is 15 days, while on Alibaba Cloud it&amp;rsquo;s less than 5 days&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning renting for this period allows you to purchase the entire disk outright. If you opt for a three-year prepaid purchase on Alibaba Cloud with the maximum discount of 50%, &lt;strong&gt;the three-year rental fee could buy over 120 similar disks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/blog/cloud/finops-3.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/ebs/&#34;&gt;EBS: a real Scam&lt;/a&gt;》&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The price markup ratio of cloud databases (RDS) falls between that of cloud disks and cloud servers. For example, using RDS for PostgreSQL on AWS, a 64C / 256GB RDS costs $25,817 per month, equivalent to 180,000 yuan per month. One month&amp;rsquo;s rent is enough to purchase two servers with much better performance for in-house use. &lt;strong&gt;The rent-to-buy ratio is not even a month&lt;/strong&gt;; renting for just over ten days would be enough to purchase an entire server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any rational enterprise user can see the folly in this: &lt;strong&gt;If the procurement of such services is not for short-term, temporary needs, then it definitely qualifies as a significant financial misjudgment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Payment Model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cost Per Year (¥10k)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Self-hosted IDC (Single Physical Server)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥75k / 5 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Self-hosted IDC (2-3 Server HA Cluster)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥150k / 5 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.0 ~ 4.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba Cloud RDS (On-demand)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥87.36/hour&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;76.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba Cloud RDS (Monthly)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥42k / month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba Cloud RDS (Yearly, 15% off)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥425,095 / year&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;42.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba Cloud RDS (3-year, 50% off)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥750,168 / 3 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS (On-demand)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$25,817 / month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;217&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS (1-year, no upfront)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$22,827 / month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;191.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS (3-year, full upfront)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$120k + $17.5k/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;175&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS China/Ningxia (On-demand)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥197,489 / month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;237&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS China/Ningxia (1-year, no upfront)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥143,176 / month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;171&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS China/Ningxia (3-year, full upfront)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥647k + ¥116k/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;160.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing the costs of self-hosting versus using a cloud database:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Method&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cost Per Year (¥10k)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Self-hosted Servers 64C / 384G / 3.2TB NVME SSD 660K IOPS (2-3 servers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.0 ~ 4.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba Cloud RDS PG High-Availability pg.x4m.8xlarge.2c, 64C / 256GB / 3.2TB ESSD PL3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25 ~ 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS RDS PG High-Availability db.m5.16xlarge, 64C / 256GB / 3.2TB io1 x 80k IOPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;160 ~ 217&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RDS&lt;/strong&gt; pricing compared to self-hosting, see &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/rds/&#34;&gt;Is Cloud Database an idiot Tax?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any meaningful cost reduction and efficiency increase initiative cannot ignore this issue: if there&amp;rsquo;s potential to slash resource prices by 50% to 200%, then focusing on a 30% reduction in waste is not a priority. As long as your main business is on the cloud, traditional FinOps is like scratching an itch through a boot — &lt;strong&gt;migrating off the cloud is the focal point of FinOps&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-endgame-of-finops-is-exiting-from-the-cloud&#34;&gt;The Endgame of FinOps is Exiting from the Cloud&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The well-fed do not understand the pangs of hunger, human joys and sorrows are not universally shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent five years at Tantan — a Nordic-style internet startup founded by a Swede. Nordic engineers have a characteristic pragmatism. When it comes to choosing between cloud and on-premise solutions, they are not swayed by hype or marketing but rather make decisions based on quantitative analysis of pros and cons. We meticulously calculated the costs of building our own infrastructure versus using the cloud — the straightforward conclusion was that &lt;strong&gt;the total cost of on-premise solutions (including labor) generally fluctuates between 10% to 100% of the list price for cloud services&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, from its inception, Tantan chose to build its own infrastructure. Apart from overseas compliance businesses, CDN, and a very small amount of elastic services using public clouds, the main part of our operations was entirely hosted in IDC-managed data centers. Our database was not small, with 13K cores for PostgreSQL and 12K cores for Redis, 4.5 million QPS, and 300TB of unique transactional data. The annual cost for these two parts was less than 10 million yuan: including salaries for two DBAs, one network engineer, network and electricity, managed hosting fees, and hardware amortized over five years. However, for such a scale, if we were to use cloud databases, even with significant discounts, the starting cost would be between 50 to 60 million yuan, not to mention the even more expensive big data sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, digitalization in enterprises is phased, and different companies are at different stages. For many internet companies, they have reached the stage where they are fully engaged with building cloud-native K8S ecosystems. At this stage, focusing on resource utilization, mixed online and offline deployments, and reducing waste are reasonable demands and directions where FinOps should concentrate its efforts. Yet, for the vast majority of enterprises outside the digital realm, the urgent need is not reducing waste but &lt;strong&gt;lowering the unit cost of resources&lt;/strong&gt; — Dell servers can be discounted by 50%, IDC virtual machines by 50%, and even cloud services can be heavily discounted. Are these companies still paying the list price, or even facing several times the markup in rebates? &lt;strong&gt;A great many companies are still being severely exploited due to information asymmetry and lack of capability&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprises should evaluate their scale and stage, assess their business, and weigh the pros and cons accordingly. For small-scale startups, the cloud can indeed save a lot of manpower costs, which is very attractive — &lt;strong&gt;but please be cautious not to be locked in by vendors due to the convenience offered&lt;/strong&gt;. If your annual cloud expenditure has already exceeded 1 million yuan, it&amp;rsquo;s time to seriously consider &lt;strong&gt;the benefits of descending from the cloud&lt;/strong&gt; — many businesses do not require the elasticity for massive concurrent spikes or training AI models. Paying a premium for temporary/sudden needs or overseas compliance is reasonable, but paying several times to tens of times more for &lt;strong&gt;unnecessary elasticity&lt;/strong&gt; is wasteful. You can keep the truly elastic parts of your operations on the public cloud and transfer those parts that do not require elasticity to IDCs. Just by doing this, the cost savings could be astonishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descending from the cloud is the ultimate goal of traditional FinOps and the starting point of true FinOps.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;self-hosting-matters&#34;&gt;Self-Hosting Matters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To seek peace through struggle is to preserve peace; to seek peace through compromise is to lose peace.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the times are favorable, the world joins forces; when fortune fades, even heroes lose their freedom: During the bubble phase, it was easy to disregard spending heavily in the cloud. However, in an economic downturn, cost reduction and efficiency become central themes. An increasing number of companies are realizing that using cloud services is essentially paying a &amp;ldquo;no-expert tax&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;protection money&amp;rdquo;. Consequently, a trend of &amp;ldquo;cloud repatriation&amp;rdquo; has emerged, with 37Signals&amp;rsquo; DHH being one of the most notable proponents. Correspondingly, the revenue growth rate of major cloud providers worldwide has been experiencing a continuous decline, with Alibaba Cloud&amp;rsquo;s revenue even starting to shrink in the first quarter of 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/blog/cloud/finops-5.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/profit/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why Cloud Computing Hasn&amp;rsquo;t Yet Hit Its Stride in Earning Profits&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;》&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying trend is the emergence of &lt;strong&gt;open-source alternatives&lt;/strong&gt;, breaking down the &lt;strong&gt;technical barriers&lt;/strong&gt; of public clouds; the advent of resource clouds/IDC2.0, offering a cost-effective alternative to public cloud resources; and the release of technical talents from large layoffs, along with the future of AI models, giving every industry the opportunity to possess the expert knowledge and capability required for self-hosting. Combining these trends, &lt;strong&gt;the combination of IDC2.0 + open-source self-hosting is becoming increasingly competitive&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Bypassing the public cloud intermediaries and working directly with IDCs is clearly a more economical choice&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public cloud providers are not incapable of engaging in the business of selling IDC resources profitably. Given their higher level of expertise compared to IDCs, they should, in theory, leverage their technological advantages and economies of scale to offer cheaper resources than IDC self-hosting. However, the harsh reality is that resource clouds can offer users virtual machines at a 80% discount, while public clouds cannot. Even considering the exponential growth law of Moore&amp;rsquo;s Law in the storage and computing industry, public clouds are actually &lt;strong&gt;increasing their prices&lt;/strong&gt; every year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well-informed major clients, especially those capable of migrating at will, can indeed negotiate for &lt;strong&gt;80% off&lt;/strong&gt; the list prices with public clouds, a feat unlikely for smaller clients — in this sense, &lt;strong&gt;clouds are essentially subsidizing large clients by bleeding small and medium-sized clients dry&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Cloud vendors offer massive discounts to large clients while fleecing small and medium-sized clients and developers&lt;/strong&gt;, completely contradicting the original intention and vision of cloud computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clouds lure in users with low initial prices, but once users are deeply locked in, the slaughter begins — the previously discussed discounts and benefits disappear at each renewal. Escaping the cloud entails a significant cost, leaving users in a dilemma between a rock and a hard place, forced to continue paying protection money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, for users with the capability to self-host, capable of flexibly moving between multi-cloud and on-premises hybrid clouds, this is not an issue: &lt;strong&gt;The trump card in negotiations is the ability to go off-cloud or migrate to another cloud at any time&lt;/strong&gt;. This is more effective than any argument — as the saying goes, &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;To seek peace through struggle is to preserve peace; to seek peace through compromise is to lose peace&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;The extent of cost reduction depends on your bargaining power, which in turn depends on your ability to self-host&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-hosting might seem daunting, but it is not difficult for those who know how&lt;/strong&gt;. The key is addressing the core issues of &lt;strong&gt;resources&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;. In 2023, due to the emergence of resource clouds and open-source alternatives, these issues have become much simpler than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In terms of resources, IDC and resource clouds have solved the problem adequately&lt;/strong&gt;. The aforementioned IDC self-hosting doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean buying land and building data centers from scratch but directly using the hosting services of resource clouds/IDCs — you might only need a network engineer to plan the network, with other maintenance tasks managed by the provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you prefer not to hassle, IDCs can directly sell you virtual machines at 20% of the list price, or you can rent a physical server with 64C/256G for a couple thousand a month; whether renting an entire data center or just a single colocation space, it&amp;rsquo;s all feasible. A retail colocation space with comprehensive services can be settled for about five thousand a year, running a K8S or virtualization on a couple of hundred-core physical servers, why bother with flexible ECS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finops-leads-to-cloud-exit&#34;&gt;FinOps Leads to CLoud-Exit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building your own infrastructure comes with the added perk of extreme FinOps—utilizing out-of-warranty or even second-hand servers. Servers are typically depreciated over three to five years, yet it&amp;rsquo;s not rare to see them operational for eight to ten years. This contrasts with cloud services, where you&amp;rsquo;re just consuming resources; owning your server translates to tangible assets, making any extended use essentially a gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, a new 64-core, 256GB server could cost around $7,000, but after a year or two, the price for such &amp;ldquo;electronic waste&amp;rdquo; drops to merely $400.
By replacing the most failure-prone components with brand new enterprise-grade 3.2TB NVMe SSDs (costing $390), you could secure the entire setup for just $800.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such scenarios, your vCPU·Month price could plummet to less than $0.15, a figure legendary in the gaming industry, where server costs can dip to mere cents.
With Kubernetes (K8S) orchestration and database high-availability switching, reliability can be assured through parallel operation of multiple such servers, achieving an astonishing cost-efficiency ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of capability, with the emergence of sufficiently robust open-source alternatives, the difficulty of self-hosting has dramatically decreased compared to a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, Kubernetes/OpenStack/SealOS are open-source alternatives to cloud providers&amp;rsquo; EC2/ECS/VPS management software; MinIO/Ceph aim to replace S3/OSS; while Pigsty and various database operators serve as open-source substitutes for RDS cloud database management. There&amp;rsquo;s a plethora of open-source software available for effectively utilizing these resources, along with numerous commercial entities offering transparently priced support services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your operations should ideally converge to using just virtual machines and object storage, the lowest common denominator across all cloud providers. Ideally, all applications should run on Kubernetes, which can operate in any environment—be it a cloud-hosted K8S, ECS, dedicated servers, or your own data center. External states like database backups and big data warehouses should be managed with compute-storage separation, using MinIO/S3 storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a CloudNative tech stack theoretically enables operation and flexible migration across any resource environment, thus avoiding vendor lock-in and maintaining control. This allows you to either significantly cut costs by moving off the cloud or leverage it to negotiate discounts with public cloud providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, self-hosting isn&amp;rsquo;t without risks, with RDS representing a major potential vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;database-the-biggest-risk-factor&#34;&gt;Database: The Biggest Risk Factor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud databases&lt;/strong&gt; may not be the most expensive line item, but they are definitely the most deeply locked-in and challenging to migrate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality, security, efficiency, and cost represent different levels of a hierarchical pyramid of needs. The goal of FinOps is to reduce costs and increase efficiency &lt;strong&gt;without compromising quality and security&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stateless apps on K8S or offline big data platforms pose little fatal risk when migrating. Especially if you have already achieved &lt;strong&gt;big data compute-storage separation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;stateless app cloud-native&lt;/strong&gt; transformation, moving these components is generally not too troublesome. The former can afford a few hours of downtime, while the latter can be updated through blue-green deployments and canary releases. &lt;strong&gt;The database, serving as the working memory, is prone to major issues when migrated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most IT system architectures are centered around the database, making it the key risk point in cloud migration, particularly with OLTP databases/RDS. Many users hesitate to move off the cloud and self-host due to the lack of reliable database services — traditional Kubernetes Operators don’t fully replicate the cloud database experience: hosting OLTP databases on K8S/containers with EBS is not yet a mature practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a growing demand for a viable open-source alternative to RDS&lt;/strong&gt;, and that&amp;rsquo;s precisely what we aim to address: enabling users to establish a local RDS service in any environment that matches or exceeds cloud databases — &lt;strong&gt;Pigsty&lt;/strong&gt;, a free open-source alternative to RDS PG. It empowers users to effectively utilize &lt;a href=&#34;/zh/blog//db/pg-is-best/&#34;&gt;PostgreSQL, the world’s most advanced and successful database&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pigsty is a non-profit, open-source software powered by community love. It offers a ready-to-use, feature-rich PostgreSQL distribution with automatic high availability, PITR, top-tier monitoring systems, Infrastructure as Code, cloud-based Terraform templates, local Vagrant sandbox for one-click installation, and SOP manuals for various operations, enabling quick RDS self-setup without needing a professional DBA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Pigsty is a database distribution, it enables users to practice ultimate FinOps—running production-level PostgreSQL RDS services anywhere (ECS, resource clouds, data center servers, or even local laptop VMs) at almost pure resource cost. &lt;strong&gt;It turns the cost of cloud database capabilities from being proportional to marginal resource costs to nearly zero in fixed learning costs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/blog/cloud/finops-7.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s the socialist ethos of Nordic companies that nurtures such pure free software. Our goal isn’t profit but to promote a philosophy: to democratize the expertise of using the advanced open-source database PostgreSQL for everyone, not just cloud monopolies. Cloud providers monopolize open-source expertise and roles, exploiting free open-source software, and we aim to break this monopoly—&lt;strong&gt;Freedom is not free. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t concede the world to those you despise but rather overturn their table&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the essence of FinOps—empowering users with viable alternatives and the ability to self-host, thus negotiating with cloud providers from a position of strength&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/JU4lznF6-5Q4LaJTnG8SSQ&#34;&gt;云计算为啥还没挖沙子赚钱？&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/c8bpK4o3H7-EyRqVdNDndQ&#34;&gt;云数据库是不是智商税？&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/LC5jAhuVObRcrTLxI1FUQA&#34;&gt;云SLA是不是安慰剂？&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/UxjiUBTpb1pRUfGtR9V3ag&#34;&gt;云盘是不是杀猪盘？&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/Yp6L0hh4b4HuJQRPD3aJYw&#34;&gt;范式转移：从云到本地优先&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[6] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/TksQ108v_nGaW11-87Es3A&#34;&gt;杀猪盘真的降价了吗？&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[7] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/WsR-c64OJfkMql7zX7XmDA&#34;&gt;炮打 RDS，Pigsty v2.0 发布&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[8] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/ANFnbDXwuhKI99fgYRZ9ug&#34;&gt;垃圾腾讯云CDN：从入门到放弃&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/AGEW1iHQkQy4NQyYC2GonQ&#34;&gt;云RDS：从删库到跑路&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[10] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/-eaCoZR9Z5srQ-1YZm1QJA&#34;&gt;分布式数据库是伪需求吗？&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[11] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/mEmz8pviahEAWy1-SA8vcg&#34;&gt;微服务是不是个蠢主意？&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[12] &lt;a href=&#34;http://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzU5ODAyNTM5Ng==&amp;mid=2247485518&amp;idx=1&amp;sn=3d5f3c753facc829b2300a15df50d237&amp;chksm=fe4b3d95c93cb4833b8e80433cff46a893f939154be60a2a24ee96598f96b32271301abfda1f&amp;scene=21#wechat_redirect&#34;&gt;更好的开源RDS替代：Pigsty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: EBS: Pig Slaughter Scam</title>
      <link>/blog/cloud/ebs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cloud/ebs/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
        <![CDATA[<img src="/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/featured_hu18f662b7569a39819bc2dd9739d7776b_407025_640x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg" width="640" height="640"/>]]>
        
        &lt;p&gt;We already answer the question: &lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/rds/&#34;&gt;Is RDS an Idiot Tax?&lt;/a&gt;.
But when compared to the &lt;strong&gt;hundredfold markup of public cloud block storage&lt;/strong&gt;, cloud databases seem almost reasonable. This article uses real data to reveal the true business model of public cloud: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cheap&amp;rdquo; EC2/S3 to attract customers, and fleece with &amp;ldquo;Expensive&amp;rdquo; EBS/RDS&lt;/strong&gt;. Such practices have led public clouds to diverge from their original mission and vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/ebs/#tl-dr&#34;&gt;TLDR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/ebs/#what-a-scam&#34;&gt;WHAT a Scam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/ebs/#why-so-pricing&#34;&gt;WHY so pricing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/ebs/#how-to-do-that&#34;&gt;HOW to do that&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/ebs/#the-forgotten-vision&#34;&gt;The Forgotten Vision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/ebs/#where-to-go&#34;&gt;Where to Go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/ebs/#references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/UxjiUBTpb1pRUfGtR9V3ag&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/featured.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL; DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EC2/S3/EBS pricing serves as the anchor for all cloud services pricing. While the pricing for EC2/S3 might still be considered reasonable, EBS pricing is outright extortionate. The best block storage services offered by public cloud providers are essentially on par with off-the-shelf PCI-E NVMe SSDs in terms of performance specifications. Yet, compared to direct hardware purchases, &lt;strong&gt;the cost of AWS EBS can be up to 60 times higher, and Alibaba Cloud&amp;rsquo;s ESSD can reach up to 100 times higher.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is there such a staggering markup for plug-and-play disk hardware? Cloud providers fail to justify the exorbitant prices. When considering the design and pricing models of other cloud storage services, there&amp;rsquo;s only one plausible explanation: &lt;strong&gt;The high markup on EBS is a deliberately set barrier, intended to fleece cloud database customers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With EC2 and EBS serving as the pricing anchors for cloud databases, their markups are several and several dozen times higher, respectively, thus supporting the exorbitant profit margins of cloud databases. However, such monopolistic profits are unsustainable: the impact of IDC 2.0/telecom/national cloud on IaaS; private cloud/cloud-native/open source as alternatives to PaaS; and the tech industry&amp;rsquo;s massive layoffs, AI disruption, and the impact of China&amp;rsquo;s low labor costs on cloud services (through IT outsourcing/shared expertise). &lt;strong&gt;If public clouds continue to adhere to their current fleecing model, diverging from their original mission of providing fundamental compute and storage infrastructure, they will inevitably face increasingly severe competition and challenges from the aforementioned forces.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-a-scam&#34;&gt;WHAT a Scam!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you use a microwave at home to heat up a ready-to-eat braised chicken rice meal costing 10 yuan, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind if a restaurant charges you 30 yuan for microwaving the same meal and serving it to you, considering the costs of rent, utilities, labor, and service. But what if the restaurant charges you 1000 yuan for the same dish, claiming: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;What we offer is not just braised chicken rice, but a reliable and flexible dining service&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, with the chef controlling the quality and cooking time, pay-per-portion so you get exactly as much as you want, pay-per-need so you get as much as you eat, with options to switch to hot and spicy soup or skewers if you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like chicken, claiming it&amp;rsquo;s all worth the price. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you feel the urge to give the owner a piece of your mind? This is exactly what&amp;rsquo;s happening with block storage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With hardware technology evolving rapidly, &lt;strong&gt;PCI-E NVMe SSDs&lt;/strong&gt; have reached a new level of performance across various metrics. A common 3.2 TB enterprise-grade MLC SSD offers incredible performance, reliability, and value for money, costing less than ¥3000, significantly outperforming older storage solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/ebs-1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aliyun ESSD PL3 and our own IDC&amp;rsquo;s procured PCI-E NVMe SSDs come from the same supplier. Hence, their maximum capacity and IOPS limitations are identical. AWS&amp;rsquo;s top-tier block storage solution, io2 Block Express, also shares similar specifications and metrics. Cloud providers&amp;rsquo; highest-end storage solutions utilize these 32TB single cards, leading to a maximum capacity limit of 32TB (64TB for AWS), which suggests a high degree of hardware consistency underneath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/ebs-2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, compared to direct hardware procurement, &lt;strong&gt;the cost of AWS EBS io2 is up to 120 times higher, while Aliyun&amp;rsquo;s ESSD PL3 is up to 200 times higher&lt;/strong&gt;. Taking a 3.2TB enterprise-grade PCI-E SSD card as a reference, the ratio of on-demand rental to purchase price is 15 days on AWS and less than 5 days on Aliyun, meaning you could own the entire disk after renting it for this duration. If you opt for a three-year prepaid purchase on Aliyun, taking advantage of the maximum 50% discount, the rental fees over three years could buy over 120 disks of the same model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/ebs-3.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that SSD made of gold ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud providers argue that block storage should be compared to SAN&lt;/strong&gt; rather than local DAS, which should be compared to &lt;strong&gt;instance storage (Host Storage)&lt;/strong&gt; on the cloud. However, public cloud instance storage is generally ephemeral (Ephemeral Storage), with data being wiped once the instance is paused/stopped【7,11】, making it unsuitable for serious production databases. Cloud providers themselves advise against storing critical data on it. Therefore, the only viable option for database storage is EBS block storage. Products like DBFS, which have similar performance and cost metrics to EBS, are also included in this category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, users care not about whether the underlying hardware is SAN, SSD, or HDD; the real priorities are tangible metrics: &lt;strong&gt;latency, IOPS, reliability, and cost&lt;/strong&gt;. Comparing local options with the best cloud solutions poses no issue, especially when the top-tier cloud storage uses the same local disks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some &amp;ldquo;experts&amp;rdquo; claim that cloud block storage is stable and reliable, offering multi-replica redundancy and error correction. In the past, Share Everything databases required SAN storage, but many databases now operate on a Share Nothing architecture. Redundancy is managed at the database instance level, eliminating the need for triple-replica storage redundancy, especially since enterprise-grade disks already possess strong self-correction capabilities and safety redundancy (UBER &amp;lt; 1e-18). &lt;strong&gt;With redundancy already in place at the database level, multi-replica block storage becomes an unnecessary waste for databases&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if cloud providers did use two additional replicas for redundancy, it would only reduce the markup from 200x to 66x, without fundamentally changing the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Experts&amp;rdquo; also liken purchasing &amp;ldquo;cloud services&amp;rdquo; to buying insurance&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;An annual failure rate of 0.02% may seem negligible to most, but a single incident can be devastating, with the cloud provider offering a safety net.&amp;rdquo; This sounds appealing, but a closer look at cloud providers&amp;rsquo; EBS SLAs reveals no guarantees for reliability. ESSD cloud disk promotions mention 9 nines of data reliability, but such claims are conspicuously absent from the SLAs. &lt;strong&gt;Cloud providers only guarantee availability, and even then, the guarantees are modest&lt;/strong&gt;, as illustrated by the AWS EBS SLA:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/ebs-4.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/sla/&#34;&gt;Is the Cloud SLA Just a Placebo?&lt;/a&gt;》&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In plain language: if the service is down for a day and a half in a month (95% availability), you get a 100% coupon for that month&amp;rsquo;s service fee; seven hours of downtime (99%) yields a 30% coupon; and a few minutes of downtime (99.9% for a single disk, 99.99% for a region) earns a 10% coupon. Cloud providers charge a hundredfold more, yet offer mere coupons as compensation for significant outages. Applications that can&amp;rsquo;t tolerate even a few minutes of downtime wouldn&amp;rsquo;t benefit from these meager coupons, reminiscent of the past incident, &amp;ldquo;The Disaster Tencent Cloud Brought to a Startup Company.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SF Express offers 1% insurance for parcels, compensating for losses with real money. Annual commercial health insurance plans costing tens of thousands can cover millions in expenses when issues arise. The insurance industry should not be insulted; it operates on a principle of value for money. &lt;strong&gt;Thus, an SLA is not an insurance policy against losses for users. At worst, it&amp;rsquo;s a bitter pill to swallow without recourse; at best, it provides emotional comfort.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premium charged for cloud database services might be justified by &amp;ldquo;expert manpower,&amp;rdquo; but this rationale falls flat for plug-and-play disks, &lt;strong&gt;with cloud providers unable to explain the exorbitant price markup&lt;/strong&gt;. When pressed, their engineers might only say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re just following AWS; that&amp;rsquo;s how they designed it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-so-pricing&#34;&gt;WHY so Pricing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even engineers within public cloud services may not fully grasp the rationale behind their pricing strategies, and those who do are unlikely to share. However, this does not prevent us from deducing the reasoning behind such decisions from the &lt;strong&gt;design of the product&lt;/strong&gt; itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storage follows a de facto standard: &lt;strong&gt;POSIX file system + block storage&lt;/strong&gt;. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s database files, images, audio, or video, they all use the same file system interface to store data on disks. But AWS&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;divine intervention&amp;rdquo; splits this into two distinct services: &lt;strong&gt;S3&lt;/strong&gt; (Simple Storage Service) and &lt;strong&gt;EBS&lt;/strong&gt; (Elastic Block Store). Many &amp;ldquo;followers&amp;rdquo; have imitated AWS&amp;rsquo;s product design and pricing model, yet the logic and principles behind such actions remain elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/ebs-5.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aliyun EBS OSS Compare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S3&lt;/strong&gt;, standing for &lt;strong&gt;Simple Storage Service&lt;/strong&gt;, is a simplified alternative to file system/storage: sacrificing strong consistency, directory management, and access latency for the sake of low cost and massive scalability. It offers a simple, high-latency, high-throughput flat KV storage service, detached from standard storage services. This aspect, being cost-effective, serves as a major allure for users to migrate to the cloud, thus becoming possibly the only &lt;strong&gt;de facto cloud computing standard across all public cloud providers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databases, on the other hand, require low latency, strong consistency, high quality, high performance, and random read/write block storage&lt;/strong&gt;, which is encapsulated in the EBS service: Elastic Block Store. This segment becomes the forbidden fruit for cloud providers: reluctant to let users dabble. &lt;strong&gt;Because EBS serves as the pricing anchor for RDS — the barrier and moat for cloud databases&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For IaaS providers, who make their living by selling resources, there&amp;rsquo;s not much room for price inflation, as costs can be precisely calculated against the BOM. However, for PaaS services like cloud databases, which include &amp;ldquo;services,&amp;rdquo; labor/development costs are significantly marked up, allowing for &lt;strong&gt;astronomical pricing&lt;/strong&gt; and high profits. Despite storage, computing, and networking making up half of the revenue for domestic public cloud IaaS, their gross margin stands only at &lt;strong&gt;15% to 20%&lt;/strong&gt;. In contrast, public cloud PaaS, represented by cloud databases, can achieve gross margins of &lt;strong&gt;50%&lt;/strong&gt; or higher, vastly outperforming the IaaS model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If users opt to use IaaS resources (EC2/EBS) to build their own databases, it represents a significant loss of profit for cloud providers. Thus, cloud providers go to great lengths to prevent this scenario. But how is such a product designed to meet this need?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, &lt;strong&gt;instance storage&lt;/strong&gt;, which is best suited for self-hosted databases, must come with various restrictions: instances that are hibernated/stopped are reclaimed and wiped, preventing serious production database services from running on EC2&amp;rsquo;s built-in disks. Although EBS&amp;rsquo;s performance and reliability might slightly lag behind local NVMe SSD storage, it&amp;rsquo;s still viable for database operations, hence the restrictions: but not without giving users an option, hence the &lt;strong&gt;exorbitant pricing&lt;/strong&gt;! As compensation, the secondary, cheaper, and massive storage option, S3, can be priced more affordably to lure customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, to make customers bite, some cloud computing KOLs promote the accompanying &amp;ldquo;public cloud-native&amp;rdquo; philosophy: &amp;ldquo;EC2 is not suitable for stateful applications. Please store state in S3 or RDS and other managed services, as these are the &amp;lsquo;best practices&amp;rsquo; for using our cloud.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/ebs-7.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These four points are well summarized, but what public clouds will not disclose is the cost of these &amp;ldquo;best practices.&amp;rdquo; To put &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lipingtababa/cloud-native-best-practices/blob/main/%E4%BA%91%E5%8E%9F%E7%94%9F%E7%8E%8B%E5%9B%9B%E6%9D%A1.md&#34;&gt;these four points&lt;/a&gt; in layman&amp;rsquo;s terms, they form a carefully designed trap for customers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dump ordinary files in S3!&lt;/strong&gt; (With such cost-effective S3, who needs EBS?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t build your own database!&lt;/strong&gt; (Forget about tinkering with open-source alternatives using instance storage)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please deeply use the vendor&amp;rsquo;s proprietary identity system&lt;/strong&gt; (vendor lock-in)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faithfully contribute to the cloud database!&lt;/strong&gt; (Once users are locked in, the time to &amp;ldquo;slaughter&amp;rdquo; arrives)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-do-that&#34;&gt;HOW to Do that&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The business model of public clouds can be summarized as: &lt;strong&gt;Attract customers with cheap EC2/S3, make a killing with EBS/RDS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To slaughter the pig, you first need to raise it. No pains, no gains. Thus, for new users, startups, and small-to-medium enterprises, public clouds spare no effort in offering sweeteners, even at a loss, to drum up business. New users enjoy a significant discount on their first order, startups receive free or half-price credits, and the pricing strategy is subtly crafted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking AWS RDS &lt;a href=&#34;https://instances.vantage.sh/&#34;&gt;pricing&lt;/a&gt; as an example, the unit price for mini models with 1 to 2 cores is only &lt;strong&gt;a few dollars per core per month&lt;/strong&gt;, which translates to three to four hundred yuan per year (excluding storage): If you need a low-usage database for minor storage, this might be the most straightforward and affordable choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://instances.vantage.sh/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/ebs-8.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;as soon as you slightly increase the configuration, even by just a little, the price per core per month jumps by orders of magnitude&lt;/strong&gt;, reaching twenty to a hundred dollars, with the potential to skyrocket by dozens of times — &lt;strong&gt;and that&amp;rsquo;s before the doubling effect of the astonishing EBS prices&lt;/strong&gt;. Users only realize what has happened when they are faced with a suddenly astronomical bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, using RDS for PostgreSQL on AWS, the price for a 64C / 256GB db.m5.16xlarge RDS for one month is $25,817, which is equivalent to about 180,000 yuan per month. The monthly rent is enough for you to buy two servers with even better performance and set them up on your own. &lt;strong&gt;The rent-to-buy ratio doesn&amp;rsquo;t even last a month; renting for just over ten days is enough to buy the whole server for yourself&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Payment Model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cost Per Year (¥10k)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Self-hosted IDC (Single Physical Server)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥75k / 5 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Self-hosted IDC (2-3 Server HA Cluster)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥150k / 5 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.0 ~ 4.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba Cloud RDS (On-demand)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥87.36/hour&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;76.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba Cloud RDS (Monthly)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥42k / month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba Cloud RDS (Yearly, 15% off)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥425,095 / year&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;42.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba Cloud RDS (3-year, 50% off)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥750,168 / 3 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS (On-demand)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$25,817 / month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;217&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS (1-year, no upfront)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$22,827 / month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;191.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS (3-year, full upfront)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$120k + $17.5k/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;175&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS China/Ningxia (On-demand)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥197,489 / month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;237&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS China/Ningxia (1-year, no upfront)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥143,176 / month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;171&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS China/Ningxia (3-year, full upfront)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¥647k + ¥116k/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;160.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing the costs of self-hosting versus using a cloud database:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Method&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cost Per Year (¥10k)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Self-hosted Servers 64C / 384G / 3.2TB NVME SSD 660K IOPS (2-3 servers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.0 ~ 4.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba Cloud RDS PG High-Availability pg.x4m.8xlarge.2c, 64C / 256GB / 3.2TB ESSD PL3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25 ~ 50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AWS RDS PG High-Availability db.m5.16xlarge, 64C / 256GB / 3.2TB io1 x 80k IOPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;160 ~ 217&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RDS&lt;/strong&gt; pricing compared to self-hosting, see &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/rds/&#34;&gt;Is Cloud Database an idiot Tax?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any rational business user can see the logic here: **If the purchase of such a service is not for short-term, temporary needs, then it is definitely considered a &lt;strong&gt;major financial misstep&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not just the case with Relational Database Services / RDS, but with all sorts of cloud databases. MongoDB, ClickHouse, Cassandra, if it uses EC2 / EBS, they are all doing the same. Take the popular NoSQL document database MongoDB as an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of pricing could only come from a product manager without a decade-long cerebral thrombosis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Five years is the typical depreciation period for servers&lt;/strong&gt;, and with the maximum discount, a 12-node (64C 512G) configuration is priced at twenty-three million. The minor part of this quote alone could easily cover the five-year hardware maintenance, plus you could afford a team of MongoDB experts to customize and set up as you wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fine dining restaurants charge a 15% service fee on dishes, and users can understand and support this reasonable profit margin&lt;/strong&gt;. If cloud databases charge a few tens of percent on top of hardware resources for service fees and elasticity premiums (let&amp;rsquo;s not even start on software costs for cloud services that piggyback on open-source), it can be justified as pricing for productive elements, with the problems solved and services provided being worth the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, charging several hundred or even thousands of percent as a premium falls into the category of &lt;strong&gt;destructive element distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: cloud providers bank on the fact that once users are onboard, they have no alternatives, and migration would incur significant costs, so they can confidently proceed with the slaughter! In this sense, the money users pay is not for the service, but rather a compulsory levy of a &amp;ldquo;no-expert tax&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;protection money&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-forgotten-vision&#34;&gt;The Forgotten Vision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facing accusations of &amp;ldquo;slaughtering the pig,&amp;rdquo; cloud vendors often defend themselves by saying: &amp;ldquo;Oh, what you&amp;rsquo;re seeing is the list price. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s said to be a minimum of 50% off, but for major customers, there are no limits to the discounts.&amp;rdquo; As a rule of thumb: &lt;strong&gt;the cost of self-hosting fluctuates around 5% to 10% of the current cloud service list prices&lt;/strong&gt;. If such discounts can be maintained long-term, cloud services become more competitive than self-hosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professional and knowledgeable large customers, especially those capable of migrating at any time, can indeed negotiate steep discounts of up to 80% with public clouds, while smaller customers naturally lack bargaining power and are unlikely to secure such deals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;cloud computing should not turn into &amp;lsquo;calculating clouds&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;: if cloud providers can only offer massive discounts to large enterprises while &amp;ldquo;shearing the sheep&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;slaughtering the pig&amp;rdquo; when dealing with small and medium-sized customers and developers, they are essentially &lt;strong&gt;robbing the poor to subsidize the rich&lt;/strong&gt;. This practice completely contradicts the original intent and vision of cloud computing and is unsustainable in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When cloud computing first emerged, the focus was on the &lt;strong&gt;cloud hardware / IaaS layer&lt;/strong&gt;: computing power, storage, bandwidth. Cloud hardware represents the founding story of cloud vendors: to make computing and storage resources as accessible as utilities, with themselves playing the role of infrastructure providers. This is a compelling vision: public cloud vendors can reduce hardware costs and spread labor costs through economies of scale; ideally, while keeping a profit for themselves, they can offer storage and computing power that is more cost-effective and flexible than IDC prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;cloud software (PaaS / SaaS)&lt;/strong&gt; follows a fundamentally different business logic: cloud hardware relies on economies of scale to optimize overall efficiency and earn money through resource pooling and overselling, which represents a progress in efficiency. Cloud software, however, relies on sharing expertise and charging service fees for outsourced operations and maintenance. Many services on the public cloud are essentially wrappers around free open-source software, relying on monopolizing expertise and exploiting information asymmetry to charge exorbitant insurance fees, which constitutes a transfer of value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, for the sake of obfuscation, both cloud software and cloud hardware are branded under the &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; title. Thus, the narrative of cloud computing mixes breaking resource monopolies with establishing expertise monopolies: &lt;strong&gt;it combines the idealistic glow of democratizing computing power across millions of households&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;the greed of monopolizing and unethically profiting from it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public cloud providers that abandon platform neutrality and their original intent of being infrastructure providers, indulging in PaaS / SaaS / and even application layer profiteering, will sink in a bottomless competition.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-go&#34;&gt;Where to Go&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monopolistic profits vanish as competition emerges, plunging public cloud providers into a grueling battle.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the infrastructure level, telecom operators, state-owned clouds, and IDC 1.5/2.0 have entered the fray, offering highly competitive IaaS services. These services include turnkey network and electricity hosting and maintenance, with high-end servers available for either purchase and hosting or direct rental at actual prices, showing no fear in terms of flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/ebs-11.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IDC 2.0&amp;rsquo;s new server rental model: Actual price rental, ownership transfers to the user after a full term&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the software front, what once were the technical barriers of public clouds, various management software / &lt;strong&gt;PaaS&lt;/strong&gt; solutions, have seen excellent open-source alternatives emerge. OpenStack / Kubernetes have replaced EC2, MinIO / Ceph have taken the place of S3, and on RDS, open-source alternatives like &lt;strong&gt;Pigsty&lt;/strong&gt; and various K8S Operators have appeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole &amp;ldquo;cloud-native&amp;rdquo; movement, in essence, is the open-source ecosystem&amp;rsquo;s response to the challenge of public cloud &amp;ldquo;freeloading&amp;rdquo;: &lt;strong&gt;users and developers have created a complete set of local-priority public cloud open-source alternatives to avoid being exploited by public cloud providers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/ebs-12.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;CloudNative&amp;rdquo; is aptly named, reflecting different perspectives: public clouds see it as being &amp;ldquo;born on the public cloud,&amp;rdquo; while private clouds think of it as &amp;ldquo;running cloud-like services locally.&amp;rdquo; Ironically, the biggest proponents of Kubernetes are the public clouds themselves, akin to a salesman crafting his own noose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of economic downturn, cost reduction and efficiency gains have become the main theme. Massive layoffs in the tech sector, coupled with the future large-scale impact of AI on intellectual industries, will release a large amount of related talent. Additionally, the low-wage advantage in our era will significantly alleviate the scarcity and high cost of building one&amp;rsquo;s own talent pool. Labor costs, in comparison to cloud service costs, offer much more advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering these trends, the combination of IDC2.0 and open-source self-building is becoming increasingly competitive: for organizations with a bit of scale and talent reserves, bypassing public clouds as middlemen and directly collaborating with IDCs is clearly a more economical choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staying true to the original mission is essential. Public clouds do an admirable job at the cloud hardware / IaaS level, except for being outrageously expensive, there aren’t many issues, and the offerings are indeed solid. If they could return to their original vision and truly excel as providers of basic infrastructure, akin to utilities, selling resources might not offer high margins, but it would allow them to earn money standing up. Continuing down the path of exploitation, however, will ultimately lead customers to vote with their feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/zh/blog/cloud/ebs/ebs-13.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【1】&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/w5XKsXf_NLWnKB6G-sbZaw&#34;&gt;撤离 AWS：3年省下27.5亿元&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【2】&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/rds/&#34;&gt;云数据库是不是智商税&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【3】&lt;a href=&#34;/blog/cloud/paradigm/&#34;&gt;范式转移：从云到本地优先&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【4】&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/ANFnbDXwuhKI99fgYRZ9ug&#34;&gt;腾讯云CDN：从入门到放弃&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【5】&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/WsR-c64OJfkMql7zX7XmDA&#34;&gt;炮打 RDS，Pigsty v2.0 发布&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【6】&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.shannon-sys.com/product.html?name=gen_4&#34;&gt;Shannon NVMe Gen4 Series&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【7】&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/InstanceStorage.html&#34;&gt;AWS实例存储&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【8】&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/cn/blogs/storage/achieve-higher-database-performance-using-amazon-ebs-io2-block-express-volumes/&#34;&gt;AWS io2 gp3 存储性能与定价&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【9】&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/cn/ebs/sla/&#34;&gt;AWS EBS SLA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【10】&lt;a href=&#34;https://instances.vantage.sh/&#34;&gt;AWS EC2 / RDS 报价查询&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【11】&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.aliyun.com/document_detail/63138.html&#34;&gt;Aliyun：Host Storage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【12】&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.aliyun.com/document_detail/25383.html&#34;&gt;阿里云：云盘概述&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【13】&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.aliyun.com/document_detail/445806.html&#34;&gt;图说块存储与云盘&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【14】&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.futunn.com/post/24656633&#34;&gt;从狂飙到集体失速，云计算换挡寻出路&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【15】&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/LC5jAhuVObRcrTLxI1FUQA&#34;&gt;云计算为啥还没挖沙子赚钱？&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
